[roars]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words…
are called…
Hunters.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Leorio!
[both gasp]
[grimacing in pain]
[Gon] Leorio!
BIG x TIME x INTERVIEW
[narrator] Gon and his group
have been trapped by vipers,
which now block their exit.
But the vipers’ master, Bourbon...
is dead.
Are you telling us that the person
who set this trap is now dead?
But how?
Well, I killed him.
But my methods are a trade secret.
Hey, Gon. Take Leorio.
[gasp]
[Ponzu] It’s no use.
I’m sorry,
but you won’t be able to search him.
The snakes are trained.
And if you even try to touch him
or you try to leave the cave and escape,
every single one of them will attack you.
[Kurapika]
So, you fought poison with poison.
Judging by his wounds,
you must have used Neurotoxic Bees.
So, it’s likely that he died
of anaphylactic shock.
“Anaphylactic”?
What is that?
When a bee stings a human,
certain antibodies are produced
in an attempt to counter the effects
of the bee’s venom.
But if that person is stung again
by the same kind of bee,
they will experience an allergic reaction.
An extreme allergic reaction
is known as anaphylactic shock.
Depending on the circumstances,
it can be fatal.
That’s what happened. You got me.
So, you killed him with bees?
Bourbon was who I drew as my target.
Once I’d confirmed he was inside the cave,
I sprayed sleeping gas into the entrance
then waited until it was safe to go in.
When I found him,
Bourbon was completely passed out.
But he had already set up his traps.
[Ponzu screaming]
And unfortunately for me,
there were snakes in the back of the cave,
hiding in crevices.
I guess the sleeping gas
didn’t reach them.
I was able to jump out of the way
just in the nick of time,
so I didn’t get bitten by them
or anything.
But that’s what triggered my own defenses
to activate.
[gasps]
That’s where you keep all your bees?
[buzzing]
If I scream, collapse,
or anything like that,
these little guys
will attack anyone nearby.
I wasn’t expecting him to die, though.
How could I have known
he was allergic to bees?
And the snakes kept me from helping him.
Well not like I could’ve done anything.
You can come back now.
The problem is the person
who set the trap in the first place
died without ever having the chance
to deactivate it.
And we can’t exactly disarm it
or ask him for help.
We’re trapped with no hope for escape.
[Leorio groans]
Leorio.
[sighs]
So, it’s hopeless. I gave up.
We’re stuck until the Exam Committee
comes and saves us.
The Exam Committee?
Are you saying they’ll rescue us
from this cave?
You didn’t know?
Each of our number badges
contain transmitters.
The Examiners know where all
the applicants are located at all times,
and if someone hasn’t returned
by the deadline,
they go out and look for them.
However, if it’s lost or stolen,
then you’re on your own.
Luckily, there’s only one more day left.
Best to just give up for this year
and wait for help.
We can’t do that.
Leorio’s condition is worsening.
He needs to get to a doctor.
The Examiners aren’t going to budge
‘til it’s past the deadline.
If you don’t have your badge,
you’ll be left for dead.
This is his fault, really.
I tried to warn him.
Kurapika! Gon! Don’t come in here!!
[screaming]
All you can do for him
is pray that he can manage to hang on
until help can arrive.
No.
There’s another way.
One with a good chance of success.
But if he isn’t carrying any,
we’ll have another fatality on our hands.
[Gon] Kurapika.
-Take care of Leorio.
-But Gon...
It’s there. Don’t worry.
Gon…
Gon! Hey!
Are you crazy? What are you doing?
Didn’t you hear a word I just said?
[gulps]
[hissing]
[screams]
[grunting]
Oh, no!
He-- he’s out of his mind!
[straining]
[Gon] Found it!
[both gasp]
[Gon] Kurapika! Catch!
Gon!
Hurry! Give it... to Leorio!
There. You ready, Gon?
Yeah…
I don’t believe it.
He jumped into a nest of snakes
looking for an antidote
he wasn’t sure was there!
[Kurapika]
True, but the odds were in his favor.
If you poison someone,
you can’t bargain
unless you have the antidote.
Yeah, but it was still pretty risky.
[Kurapika] That said...
doing what Gon just did
took an incredible amount of courage.
He’s stabilizing.
He should be all right.
You must be really good friends.
Hey! Do you have
any of your sleeping gas left over?
I do.
Will you trade it for this?
That’s Bourbon’s badge!
And if you had it,
it would give you the six points you need.
Yeah. That’s right.
But, uh… What are you planning
to do with it?
The sleeping gas?
Use it!
We’ll put all the snakes to sleep,
then we can escape.
Releasing it in here
would be much more effective
than when I used it at the entrance.
Within five minutes,
the cave will fill with gas,
knocking all the snakes out cold.
That’s five whole minutes!
Which is way longer
than anyone can hold their breath!
I mean, what’s the point in trying
if we’re all just going
to put ourselves to sleep in the process?
Nine minutes and 44 seconds.
What?
My record for holding my breath.
You can count on me.
I’ll carry you out of here.
Why should I trust you?
You’re just gonna leave me here
and escape by yourself.
You believe that?
You saw what he did.
Gon braved a nest of venomous snakes
to save Leorio.
[Gon] Trust me.
I’ll get you out.
I promise I will.
It’s ready to go.
[Gon] Wait for my signal,
then release the gas.
Ready and waiting.
[exhales]
[takes a deep inhale and holds breath]
[inhales and passes out]
[Gon] 199.
200.
201.
202.
203.
204.
205. [Gon's voice fading out]
206.
207.
[big exhale]
[Gon] All right!
Well I’ll leave Bourbon’s badge
here with you.
So, the Committee can find you.
Yours goes to Leorio.
That way, he’ll have his six points
and he can pass.
Consider it a small fee for saving you.
Sorry about that!
[Khara] Phase Four of the Hunter Exam
is now officially over!
All remaining applicants,
please return to the starting point
at once!
You will be given one additional hour
to make your way back.
If you still haven’t returned
by the time that hour is up,
you will fail the Exam.
Furthermore, exchanging badges
at the starting point is prohibited.
Any attempt to do so
will result in immediate disqualification.
HUNTER GLOSSARY
PONZU
[trumpets playing fanfare]
Now we will check the badges
of everyone present here.
Number 44, Mr. Hisoka.
Number 58, Mr. Pokkle.
Number 99, Mr. Killua.
Number 301, Mr. Gittarackur.
Number 191, Mr. Bodoro.
Number 294, Mr. Hanzo.
So only six applicants have passed?
Oh, wait!
Hm?
Gon!
Three more!
You’re certainly cutting it close,
aren’t you?
Killua.
[smirks]
Now the last three!
They are…
Number 404, Mr. Kurapika.
Number 403, Mr. Leorio.
And Number 405, Mr. Gon.
So, these nine applicants have passed
the Fourth Phase of the Exam!
[Netero laughing]
Six of the nine that have passed
are rookies?
Marvelous, marvelous!
Has that ever happened before?
Ah. Well, there has been a trend lately.
We’ll sometimes
go several years in a row
without a single rookie
worthy of qualifying.
And then we’ll suddenly have
a whole bunch of promising newbies apply.
This makes four times
since I became Chairman.
By the way, sir,
what will we be doing for the Final Phase?
Oh yeah, that’s right!
You haven’t told us
what you have planned yet!
Ah, yes. Well, about that…
They’ll be participating
in a rather peculiar fight.
Hm?
A “peculiar fight”, you say?
Gather the nine remaining applicants.
I’d like to speak with each of them alone.
Dammit, I’m so pathetic.
The whole Fourth Phase...
I relied on you two
to do everything for me.
I promise I’ll return the favor.
So...
uh, well, thanks, you guys.
[Beans over speaker]
Attention, all applicants.
The Chairman wishes to interview you.
Really?
[Beans] When you hear your number,
come to the reception room
on the second floor.
We’ll start with number 44, Mr. Hisoka.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Please, make yourself comfortable.
Don’t tell me
that this is the Final Phase?
Not the test itself, you understand.
I just have a few questions,
mostly to satisfy my own curiosity.
Hmm...
To start with,
why do you want to become a Hunter?
[Hisoka] To be frank, I don’t. But...
Go on.
A Hunter License can be incredibly useful.
[Netero] Oh. And how so?
For example,
Hunters can often kill
without any fear of prosecution.
I understand.
Moving on to the next question…
Out of the other eight applicants,
which one are you keeping a close eye on?
Number 99.
Ooh.
405 also caught my eye,
but not like 99.
I would love to challenge him one day.
[chuckling]
Well, one last question and we’re done.
Which of the other
eight remaining applicants
would you least want to fight?
That would be number 405.
Though 99 is a close second.
[Netero] Ah...
[Hisoka] The time simply isn’t right.
As for now, I’d have to say number 405.
Hm... Understood.
However, the one I would
most like to fight right now...
would have to be you.
Well. Thank you very much.
That’ll be all.
That is one sly old man.
He left himself so open
that I lost my edge.
I’m keeping an eye focused on Number 404.
He’s the most well-rounded applicant.
But I don’t want to fight with 44.
Because... I don’t think I could beat him.
Well, Gon. We’re the same age.
Who I don’t wanna fight,
though is number 53.
I don’t think it’d be very fun at all.
I'm keeping my eye on Number 44.
You can't help but notice him.
Numbers 405 and 99 are out, however.
I simply will not fight children.
Number 99.
[clacking]
And Number 44.
Who am I keeping an eye on?
Hisoka, Number 44.
He’s on my mind the most, anyway.
But there’s no way
I could ever pick Number 99,
Number 403 or Number 404.
It has to be 44.
He’s obviously
the most dangerous applicant.
The one I’d least want to meet in combat
is also 44.
I’m watching 405,
purely for positive reasons.
44 for negative reasons.
I will fight anyone if there’s a reason.
Otherwise I’d rather not fight at all.
Number 405.
I owe him and I sure hope he passes.
That’s why he’s the one
I really don’t want to fight.
Hm, I see.
This is more lopsided than I expected.
-Gon.
-Huh?
So, we made it to the Final Phase.
HEART-SPIRIT
Hm. That'll do it.
Sorry to keep you all waiting.
I’ve drawn up the brackets.
-Huh?
-What’s this?
But-- But Chairman!
Come on! You can’t be serious!
[laughing]
Oh, I am quite serious.
That look. He’s serious indeed.
That’s a serious look? You sure?
The winners will pass the Exam
and earn the title of Hunter.
Gon.
Did something happen in the Fourth Phase?
Since we met up...
you’ve been acting strangely
and I’m getting concerned.
Ever since we left Zevil Island,
you’ve seemed rather quiet.
[Gon] My target...
was Hisoka.
I waited for the perfect chance
and stole his badge.
But someone else was following me
and he got me with a poison dart.
After that, Hisoka showed up
and took his badge
from the guy who took it from me
and then left it.
He said I owed him now.
He really said that?
[Gon] I said I didn’t need it
and he sent me flying.
[Hisoka] I will take it back
but only when you can
punch me in the face like that.
[Gon] I was just so mad at myself.
I couldn’t do anything.
I was helpless against him.
And when he left,
I got so miserable and lonely.
It was just awful.
I guess it hurt to realize
that I wasn’t strong enough
to challenge him.
That’s why I wanted some company.
I wanted to find somebody
I could help.
I guess.
That’s when I decided
to look for the two of you.
Gon...
Without your assistance,
Leorio and I
never would have made it this far.
Thank you.
For everything.
I feel the same way.
Thank you, too.
[narrator]
Gon and his friends have grown closer.
And the nine remaining applicants
are about to enter the Exam’s Final Phase.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time:
"Can't Win x And x Can't Lose"!
[Killua] Then how do I win?
[Gon] Give it all you’ve got!